Hi, I’m Marie, and welcome to LearnKey’s
course on Databases.
This course covers the material on the IT
Specialist Databases exam.
If you ever wondered how to build and manage
databases properly, this course is for you.
Building a database is not just a matter of
typing data into a spreadsheet.
There is a lot of organization involved, and
Senior Instructor, Jason Manibog, is standing
by.
This IT Specialist course on Databases is
a solid foundational course for building databases
and working with existing databases.
Not only will this course help you prepare
to take and pass the Certiport IT Specialist
Database exam, but this course will also help
you gain employability prospects in the role
of a data specialist or even a junior database
administrator.
In fact, that is the mentality I want you
to have for this course, that you are being
trained to become a junior database administrator
for a retail bicycle company.
For this course, you will want to have access
to a SQL Server installation, whether you
download and install it or have access to
one in Azure.
You will also want to get the sample AdventureWorks
database to follow along with the course videos
and projects.
Links to the SQL Server download and the sample
database tend to change, so I would use a
search engine to find both.
There are instructions for getting the database
loaded into SQL Server once you have installed
SQL Server and obtained the database.
By the way, you will want the OLTP version
of the database as that will give you the
most opportunity to practice the skills you
will learn in this course.
On to the course itself, there are five domains
in this course.
They are: Database Design, Database Object
Management, Data Retrieval, Data Manipulation,
and Troubleshooting With the course, you get
the instructional videos, pre and post-assessments
for each domain, practice labs, and a project
workbook to reinforce what you learn in this
course.
To work well with databases, one needs a solid
understanding of database design, which is
the first domain of this course, so let's
get right to the first topic, which is identifying
parts of a database.